MATIJA JAMBRESIC

Bachelor of Computer Science, Software Engineering

Gameplay and Network programmer Zagreb, Croatia

Linkedin in/mjambresic

Portfolio mjambresic.com

Github

github.com/mjambresic

Email matija.jambresic@yahoo.com

Summary

Game developer with expert skills in C# programming. Specialized in making Unity games with more than 7 years of game making and programming experience. I have a good understanding of gameplay systems, and hold a Professional Bachelor's degree in Computer Science, Software Engineering.

Skills

Expert Unity, C# Gameplay Programming Game Networking

Game-related Math UI Programming Server-Client Architecture

Game-related Physics Design patterns Data structures

Source control Git, Perforce OOP Architecture Proficient Unreal, C++

Professional Experience

Kick League - Project Owner, Gameplay Programmer

Jun 2023 - Present

After years of gaining industry experience, I decided it was the right time to consolidate my skills and build a professional product from the ground up.

- Set up the entire game architecture, ensuring clean code and fast iteration time.
- Optimized game performance, achieving over 700 fps on a 5 year old PC using proper memory caching techniques.
- Increased game related GPU performance by 50%, maintaining the same visual representation without camera stacking.
- Programmed automated tools for build uploading, boosting productivity by reducing 10 minutes of manual work to near instant computer processing.
- Implemented asynchronous loading, making game transitions feel seamless without loading screens in under 1 second.

Binx Games - Senior Gameplay, Network Programmer

Jun 2020 - Jun 2023

Remote work for a Zagreb-based studio, contributing to a multiplayer live-service game for one of the leading PC and console gaming publishers.

- One of the key programmers behind a large-scale, open-world multiplayer survival game.
- Architected a complex multiplayer backend, supporting tens of authoritative players and ensuring a fair online environment.
- Additionally, added a hybrid component to the authoritative system, supporting hundreds of non-player networked objects.
- Worked in a team that collaborated with Devolver Digital, learned about releasing games on major platforms including Steam PC and consoles like PlayStation, Xbox, and Nintendo.
- Led game settings and localization implementation for two games, reaching a global audience.

Worked on a game to rival Hearthstone, from the Zagreb office, focusing on gameplay, UI and client-side programming.

- Was part of a team that consistently achieved high performance during the months leading up to the release date, successfully clearing task boards and milestones close to 100%
- Communicated between multiple teams of artists, programmers, and management, resulting in clear and transparent workflows.
- Cooperated with audio engineers to create a sound-to-Unity import process, boosting productivity for non-technical team members.

Lionfred - Mobile Game Developer

Oct 2017 - Oct 2019

This brand encompasses several mobile game IPs that I own and created during my bachelor's degree. I designed and developed these mobile games from scratch.

- Collaborated with one of the largest casual mobile game publishers, Voodoo games.
- Designed and created more than 10 mobile game prototypes and gameplay mechanics.
- Learned about important metrics like CPI and user retention, achieving over 20% returning players in one of the prototypes.

C LAB - Software Engineer, High School Internship

2015 - 2016

Completed a programming internship over 2 weeks in 3rd grade and one day each week throughout the 4th grade, gaining my first experience in a professional programming environment.

• Undertook game-related challenges, clearing at least one challenge every week.

Education

Professional Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science, Software Engineering

Jun 2016 - Jul 2019

Međimurje University of Applied Sciences in Čakovec

- STEM Scholarship recipient, awarded to students with the best education scores in Croatia.
- Learned how to design and develop mobile, web and desktop applications.
- Developed a video game as part of the final project.

Languages

Croatian - Native

English - Fluent